Mr. Crayrat!
Oh, good. I was just about to see if you were still at home.
I've got a letter for you, sir.
Thanks. I appreciate it.
What could it be?
A letter from Paul!
Rudeus.
Word is, you got into the University of Magic.
Congratulations.
I know we've had our differences, but I'm glad you're walking your own path.
Alina Lise probably told you.
But we've got a solid lead on Zenith.
Give her my best, will ya?
Pleasantries aside, we're in Eastport now,
about to make the journey over to Begarit.
It has the second harshest terrain after the Demon Continent,
which is why I don't feel right bringing kids along.
Instead, we thought the best course of action was to send Aisha and Norn your way.
Naturally, we can't risk letting them travel by themselves.
Honestly, it was a painful decision.
I'd rather keep them close.
But as fate would have it, we ran into a familiar face.
A face you know quite well.
When he offered to escort the little ones, I knew it was the right call.
He'll be surprised to see them.
Aisha's clever like you.
She's got a good head on her shoulders.
Norn, she's a little different than the two of you.
And she kinda hates you.
She doesn't get along with Aisha either.
But, as her brother, please, be patient with her.
Anyway, you get the idea.
I feel terrible about dropping all of this on you.
But I'm grateful nonetheless.
Thanks in advance.
Yours truly, Paul.
You could cut his guilt with a knife.
But I can tell he trusts me.
Guess I gotta live up to that.
I am the oldest son after all.
Well, this familiar face.
I wonder who volunteered for the escort mission.
Guess we'll see.
Hey, Sylphie.
What's this? I hardly ever see you in such a good mood.
Well, it's because I got a letter from my dad today.
What? You heard from Paul?
Yep. Sounds like they're all fine.
Yeah? That's great!
It is. And Paul said my little sisters are coming to visit.
I know it's sudden, but I'd like them to stay with us if that's okay.
Of course. That'll liven up the house.
Thank you for this meal.
Ah, Bliss. I can't believe I actually have a place to call home, and I get to eat with the love of my life every night.
I owe Sylphie a thank you.
Hey, Sylphie. Is there anything you want me to do for you?
Yeah, teach me that spell. You know, the one you used during your entrance exam.
Oh, you mean disturb magic, right? It's so easy. I can give you the full hands-on lesson.
And in exchange, I can teach you some healing magic. I do dabble in advanced spells, if you'll recall.
Great. You're the best.
So, instead of foreplay, we ended up teaching each other magic after dinner.
Hmm.
That's weird. I don't think incantation-less healing works differently from other spells.
I wonder, maybe it's because you don't know how the person being healed feels.
She's not wrong. Attack spells are so natural to me, they're like an extension of my being.
But healing magic? That's a different story.
To be honest, it's a relief. It seems even you can't do everything.
Well, you know, when you're right, you're right.
Now it's your turn, Master Healer.
So, I've been thinking...
Please, not now! I'm trying to concentrate!
When we finally have kids, do you think they'll have our knack for magic?
Well, I guess... we won't know until we have them.
True enough.
Broody, I may have some trouble conceiving.
It's my elven blood.
So, if I'm unable to bear your children, you could enlist the help of a concubine.
Sylphie, no! Never!
It's not that I want just any children.
I want sweet little reminders of us.
I love you. For you.
Yeah. I feel the same way.
If this circle succeeds, we'll be able to move on to the next phase.
Nanahoshi spent the past month drawing this tour de force.
It's the culmination of two years' work.
Okay. Would you mind me asking what this circle is supposed to do?
Oh, it summons objects from another world.
Won't cause another mass teleportation, right?
No, it's safe. Theoretically.
And just what is this theory?
Based on our previous experiments, I've deduced that the larger and more complex the summoned object is, the more mana it requires.
Think of conservation of energy. It applies to this world's magic, too.
So, that basically means mana is responsible for most of the odd things that happen in this world.
Ah, yes.
When I conjure rocks in midair, I'm actually just transforming mana into stones. I think.
Listen time's over.
Let's get to work.
Right.
Hmm?
Something's off.
Like there's a hitch in the way the circle lights up.
Did this thing short-circuit?
Either way, it's not good.
Guess it failed.
Thanks for your help.
You can leave.
We're done here.
Hey, don't sweat it.
These things happen, you know?
Well, if you'll excuse me.
She's been awfully tense these last few months.
Judging by the way she slumped in her chair, she must be pretty rattled.
No.
Nana Hoshi's a lot tougher than she looks.
I bet she's big enough to take a failure at face value.
You?
I can't go home.
Hey, take it easy.
I'm right here.
It's going to be all right.
You've been working yourself a little too hard lately.
Take the rest of the day off.
Okay?
What happened?
I don't know.
Is she okay?
Master!
Zanoba.
Something happened to her?
She's in real trouble.
She needs help.
She's fallen ill?
More or less, yeah.
Let's get her to the infirmary, post-haste.
Master, please, allow me.
Gently, no.
Of course.
Come then, Miss Silent.
We're coming through!
If that's true, it seems she hasn't been conducting research for the pleasure of it.
I guess not.
Hey, Grandmaster?
You look awful.
Yeah, I'm an ugly piece of work.
I'll talk to Sylphie.
Nanohoshi should come and stay with us for a while.
In her current state, she shouldn't be alone.
I can think of no better option.
Would you mind carrying her home for me?
Gladly, sir.
Thank you.
Grandmaster?
What is it?
Nothing.
So, how's Zanoba treating you?
Real good.
I like him.
Yeah, he feeds to me lots of food.
Oh, really?
Good to hear.
Sounds like Master gives you a lot to eat, right?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I meant to say, yes, Master gives me a lot to eat.
Good girl.
Speaking of, I wonder if Nanohoshi's been eating enough.
Chowing down with friends, enjoying your favorite foods, does wonders for the soul.
Maybe she's been too focused on work.
We're both Japanese and share a secret, but other than that, I know almost nothing about her.
She's still asleep.
Poor thing must be exhausted.
I cast a healing spell just to be safe.
Thank you.
Sorry to interrupt.
Mm-mm.
Oh, right.
I found this when I changed her.
Might just be for work, of course.
Well, better safe than sorry.
Master, are there any signs of recovery?
Hard to tell.
Either way, I really owe you one, Zanoba.
Nonsense.
You're the one always taking care of me, after all.
What about you?
Are you all right, sir?
What's that mean?
Judging by your pallor, Miss Silence breakdown weighs on you.
I'm fine.
Just relived some bad memories, Zizal.
May I ask of what?
When I was younger, I had a very similar experience and shut down.
Well, I can't say I know the feeling.
He may not, but I do.
If things had gone just a little differently, I may have ended up like Nana Hoshi.
In any case, don't hesitate to summon me if you need any further assistance.
At the very least, I have my strength to spare.
Thanks.
I won't.
Are you hungry yet?
If you want some food, Sylphie can whip something up.
Oh, I know.
You want some potato chips?
You seem to like those, remember?
I'll heat up the bath, too.
Clean body, clean mind, they say.
Uh.
Call me if anything comes up.
I thought I'd plugged every single hole.
Magic circles are a lot like circuit boards.
When you combine the traces and components together,
they make a working circuit.
But, didn't seem to matter, did it?
That one point wouldn't connect.
It's physically impossible.
Which means, there's no hope I'm ever gonna make it home.
Okay, what do you see?
A magic circle.
Master, what exactly are we looking at here?
It's a drawing of a summoning circle Silent's been obsessing over.
She got a bit stuck, so I'd like to pick your brains.
I'm sure you're already well aware, but none of us specializes in summoning, sir.
It's alright if it's not your forte.
But since you come from different areas of study, you should have different perspectives.
Take this part as an example.
Do you see?
Looks like the mana cuts off right here.
Yeah, I think you're right.
I'd wager it's supposed to connect with this part here.
Can you think of a way to bridge the gap to get the mana running through there?
Well, those two parts go like that, and...
This is a tough one.
If we redraw it...
No way!
We can't!
Perhaps a compound design would achieve the results we need?
Never heard of that.
What do you mean?
With the doll I'm researching, there are several layers of magical circles which combine together to produce a single effect.
That being said, I've only just begun my work on it, so I have yet to actually draw a proper circle myself.
Wait!
When you say doll, you mean the one from the other day?
Let me take a look!
Hm?
Hm.
Whoever created this was a genius.
Huh?
I've never seen a circle like this.
I have no idea what makes this thing work.
Well, maybe it's just the two of them overlaid.
No, there are more layers than that.
It needs them all to function properly.
But it could still move even when it was broken.
Just what kind of circle is this?
Well, I hardly know the details yet myself.
However, according to the book, this circle controls the elbow joint.
There, there.
Genius like you will figure it out in no time, love.
Yeah, I know I will!
So, what do you think?
If we use the techniques we learned from this doll,
is that something that could help us fix the problem with Silence Circle?
I don't know.
It certainly seems possible, though.
Alright, show her what we got.
This might work.
Of course, I can see it now.
I never needed to stick to two dimensions.
Even when they're drawn on paper, they still have depth.
If I layer them, I can make as big of a circle as I need, too.
Why couldn't I think of something that was right there in front of my face?
No!
All wrong!
Wait, what about this?
Oh, right.
You're pretty smart, huh?
Uh, yeah.
Of course I am.
I'm a genius.
What should I do with this part, then?
Hang on a sec.
You could use this formula right here.
Yeah, and this part should work that way as well.
I see.
Unconventional.
Unfeasible.
All right, I'll activate it.
Unconventional.
Wow. This is quite impressive.
What is this thing?
Maybe it's a type of glass?
No, it's much too soft.
It's just a plastic bottle.
Oh, yeah. Yes!
But it's something, at least.
You've succeeded.
And that means I can finally advance to the next phase.
Layered magic circles, huh?
If I continue to improve and develop the skill, I can probably summon anything I want.
Sorry for what I put you through.
Hey, give and take, remember?
Next time I'm in a bind, lend me a hand, okay?
Yeah, I hear you.
Let's celebrate like there's no tomorrow.
Come on, it'll be your treat, of course.
Guess I have no choice.
Okay, but after that, we'll call it even, are we clear?
Cheers!
Thank you, for all your help today.
In my past life, I never went to parties like this.
Here either, for that matter.
But sometimes, when life tears you down, and your friends pick you back up, you get sucked into the moment.
It's a feeling so good you never want it to end.
How can you really live if you don't let loose every once in a while?
Life is dark, so embrace the light.
Is there anybody in there?
Hello?
Hey, Big Brother?
You know, maybe we wouldn't be here so late
if someone hadn't gotten us lost.
You sounded pretty sure it was the right way too, Aisha.
Big Brother! Big Brother!
I've missed you!
Rudeus.
It's been a long time.
Yeah? Too long, old friend.
Welcome, Rui-Jerd.
Hmm.
La, ya, la, ya, la...
M Nhà.
Ya, ya, la, ya, la!